Guide to the Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932- AIS.1998.30.16
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Dick Thornburgh Papers, Series XVI. Articles and Op-Eds
1956-2013
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Thornburgh, Dick
AIS.1998.30.16
5 Linear Feet
In the collection there are hundreds of articles and op-eds written by Dick Thornburgh, starting in 1956. Although the themes in both the op-eds and articles are highly varied, they consistently appear in Thornburgh's twenty-five year public service and ongoing careers. Nowhere is Thornburgh's leadership role in clarifying issues and serving as an advocate of positive change more evident than in these items. The articles cover legal topics, as well as Pennsylvania, national and international issues. Topics are, for example: public service, judicial reform, home rule, merit selection, organized crime, crime prevention, white collar crime, Pennsylvania's economy, economic development, jobs, education, welfare reform, Three Mile Island (TMI), energy, ethics in government, balanced budget amendment, drug abuse, terrorism, rule of law, Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA), environmental laws, United Nations, Hong Kong, civil justice reform, tort reform, science and technology, independent counsel, malpractice, and homeland security. The articles have been printed in publications such as legal journals, bulletins, newsletters, and law reviews. The op-eds written by Dick Thornburgh include many of the above topics. The primary difference is that these appear solely in newspapers. Digital reproductions of portions of the collection are available online.
Access Restrictins
No restrictions.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of op-eds through 2004 are available electronically at http://www.library.pitt.edu/thornburgh/collection/series16.html.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dick Thornburgh, February 27, 1998. Additional material acquired in 2013.
Previous Citation
Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932-, AIS.1998.30, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Pennsylvania -- Appropriations and expenditures; Politics; Environment; Civil service reform; Social action; Rule of law; Lawyers -- United States; Law -- United States; Personal papers; Government; Pennsylvania. Governor (1979-1987: Thornburgh); Three Mile Island Nuclear Power Plant (Pa.); Kirkpatrick & Lockhart; Thornburgh, Ginny (Judson); Thornburgh, Dick
- Articles and Op-Eds, 1956-2013; XVI.
  Scope and Contents note
  In this portion of the collection the researcher will find hundreds of articles and op-eds written by Dick Thornburgh from law school years up to and including Thornburgh's ongoing career.
  The myriad articles cover legal topics, as well as Pennsylvania, national and international issues. The topics include, for example: public service, judicial reform, home rule, merit selection, organized crime, crime prevention, white collar crime, Pennsylvania's economy, economic development, jobs, education, welfare reform, Three Mile Island (TMI), energy, ethics in government, balanced budget amendment, drug abuse, terrorism, rule of law, Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA), environmental laws, United Nations, Hong Kong, civil justice reform, tort reform, science and technology, independent counsel, malpractice, and homeland security.
  Although the themes are highly varied, they consistently appear over Thornburgh's twenty-five year public service and ongoing careers. Nowhere is Thornburgh's leadership role in clarifying issues and serving as an advocate of positive change more evident than in these well-crafted and interesting articles.
  The articles have been printed in legal journals, bulletins, newsletters, law reviews, and other various publications. Folders containing the articles are arranged chronologically, and there are both original copies, and frequent drafts. Of additional interest will be Thornburgh's annotations throughout.
  The op-eds written by Dick Thornburgh similarly include many of the above topics. The primary difference is that they appear solely in newspapers beginning in 1966. The newspapers include, just for example: Pittsburgh Post-Gazette, Pittsburgh Press, Washington Post, New York Times, Wall Street Journal, Philadelphia Inquirer, USA Today, Toledo Blade, Christian Science Monitor, San Francisco Chronicle, International Tribune Review, Detroit News, and Harrisburg Patriot-News.
  - Articles, 1956-2017; 1.
    - Case Note: United States v. Brown Shoes Co., University of Pittsburgh Law Review, Vol. 17, No. 4, Summer, 1956 (Box 979, Folder 1)
    - "Discovery and Federal Income Tax Return in Civil Litigation," University of Pittsburgh Law Review, Vol. 18, No. 1, Fall, 1956 (Box 979, Folder 2)
    - "Equity," University of Pittsburgh Law Review, Vol. 21, No. 2, December, 1959 (Box 979, Folder 3)
    - "Remedies," University of Pittsburgh Law Review, Vol. 22, No. 2, December, 1960 (Box 979, Folder 4)
    - "Remedies," University of Pittsburgh Law Review, Vol. 23, No. 2, December, 1961 (Box 979, Folder 5)
    - "Remedies," University of Pittsburgh Law Review, Vol. 24, No. 2, December, 1962 (Box 979, Folder 6)
    - "Remedies," University of Pittsburgh Law Review, Vol. 25, No. 2, December, 1963 (Box 979, Folder 7)
    - "Report of Junior Bar Conference," PA Bar Association Quarterly, Vol. 35, p. 136, January, 1964 (Box 979, Folder 8)
    - "Indigents in PA Criminal Courts: The Impact of Gideon v. Wainwright," PA Bar Association Quarterly, Vol. 36, No.1, p. 59, October, 1964 (Box 979, Folder 9)
    - "Report of Public Service Committee," Pittsburgh Legal Journal, Vol.115, No.1, p. 29, January, 1967 (Box 979, Folder 10)
    - "Proposed Amendments to Pennsylvania Constitution," Pittsburgh Legal Journal, Vol. 115, No. 4, p. 12, April, 1967 (Box 979, Folder 11)
    - "Report of Public Service Committee," Pittsburgh Legal Journal, Vol. 116, No. 2, p. 39, February, 1968 (Box 979, Folder 12)
    - "Review of Judiciary Article Proposed by Pennsylvania Constitutional Convention," Pittsburgh Legal Journal, Daily Edition, No. 4., March 28, 1968 (Box 979, Folder 13)
    - "Blueprint For Modern Government: A Home Rule Charter for Pittsburgh," The Pittsburgh Point, January 16, 1969 (Box 979, Folder 14)
    - "Blueprint For Modern Government: A Home Rule Charter for Pittsburgh," The Republican Voice, Vol. 4, No. 1, February, 1969 (Box 979, Folder 15)
    - "Reports of Public Service Committee," Pittsburgh Legal Journal, Vol. 117, No. 2, p. 45, February, 1969 (Box 979, Folder 16)
    - "Report of Public Service Committee," Pittsburgh Legal Journal, Vol. 117, No. 2, p. 42, February, 1970 (Box 979, Folder 17)
    - "Support Your Local Police: The Case For Strict Handgun Controls," Juris, Duquesne University Law School, Vol. VI, No. 1, 1969 (Box 979, Folder 18)
    - "Organized Crime in Western PA-We Are All Victims," Greater Pittsburgh, June, 1970 (Box 979, Folder 19)
    - "Are We Really Serious About the Crime Problem?," University of Pittsburgh Law Review, 1970 (Box 979, Folder 20)
    - "Are We Really Serious About the Crime Problem?," University of Pittsburgh Law Review, January, 1971 (Box 979, Folder 21)
    - "Metropolitan Government-Would You Repeat the Question Please?," Pittsburgh Legal Journal, No. 3, March, 1971 (Box 979, Folder 22)
    - "Metropolitanism: A Local View," Topic 22, A Journal of Liberal Arts, Washington and Jefferson College, pp. 26-30, Fall, 1971 (Box 979, Folder 23)
    - "Support the Police by Handgun Control," American Bar Association Journal, Vol. 59, pp. 404-406, April, 1973 (Box 979, Folder 24)
    - "The Case for Strict Handgun Controls," Police Times, March/April, 1973 (Box 979, Folder 25)
    - "Danger! Man With a Gun!," Milwaukee Journal, May 13, 1973 (Box 979, Folder 26)
    - "Changing Priorities in the United States Attorney's Office," Juris, Duquesne University Law School, Vol. VIII, No. 2, December, 1974 (Box 979, Folder 27)
    - "Preface," Georgetown Law Journal, Vol. 64, No. 2, December, 1975 (Box 979, Folder 28)
    - "A Professional Approach to the Career Criminal," publication unknown, excerpted from address to The Conference For a Safe Ohio, May 27, 1976 (Box 979, Folder 29)
    - "Reconciling Effective Federal Prosecution and the Fifth Amendment: 'Criminal Coddling,' 'The New Torture' or 'A Rational Accommodation?,'" Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology, Vol. 67, No. 2, pp. 155-166, 1976 (Box 979, Folder 30)
    - Letter regarding S.1. to James Smith, Executive Director Allegheny County Bar Association, Pittsburgh Legal Journal, pp. 53-59, Spring, 1976 (Box 979, Folder 31)
    - "For the Defense," Harper's, Vol. 252, No. 1512, pp. 4-6, May, 1976 (Box 979, Folder 32)
    - "A Professional Approach to the Career Criminal," LEAA Newsletter, Vol.6, No.1, pp. 2-6, June, 1976 (Box 979, Folder 33)
    - "The Federal Role in Law Enforcement," Current History, Vol. 70, No. 417, pp. 249-252, June, 1976 (Box 979, Folder 34)
    - "New Challenge Under Speedy Trial Act," New York Law Journal, August 30, 1976 (Box 979, Folder 35)
    - "Crime and Crime Prevention: What Banks Can Do," The Magazine of Bank Administration, pp. 44-46, September,1976 (Box 979, Folder 36)
    - "The Speedy Trial Act," The Judges Journal, Vol.15, No. 4, pp. 92-96, Fall, 1976 (Box 979, Folder 37)
    - "White Collar Crime," Federal Bar News, Vol. 23, No. 11, pp. 308-311, December, 1976 (Box 979, Folder 38)
    - "Band Aid Efforts Won't Solve the Crime Problem," Bar Leader, pp. 16-18, February 3, 1977 (Box 979, Folder 39)
    - "A New Agenda for Leadership," Apparel News, February, 1978 (Box 979, Folder 40)
    - "What Makes Dick Run?," The Smaller Manufacturer, pp. 5-7, March, 1978 (Box 979, Folder 41)
    - "Remarks by Dick Thornburgh," PA Fireman, April,1978 (Box 979, Folder 42)
    - "Credit Unions," Key Notes, September, 1978 (Box 979, Folder 43)
    - "The Economy and a Climate for Jobs," Apparel News, September 25, 1978 (Box 979, Folder 44)
    - "Philadelphia Schools and Pennsylvania Government," Trunk Line, September 25, 1978 (Box 979, Folder 45)
    - "Why I Can Lead"; "The Corruption Issue"; "PA's Growth Prospects"; "Taxation and Finance," four articles: Evening and Sunday Bulletin, October 9, 1978 (Box 979, Folder 46)
    - Address to Ripon Society Annual Meeting, Ripon Forum, Vol. 15, No. 5, pp. 13-14, June, 1979 (Box 980, Folder 1)
    - "Welfare Could Collapse of Its Own Weight," Criminal Justice and the Elderly, Summer, 1980 (Box 980, Folder 2)
    - "States Have Responsibility in Partnerships for Progress," National Civic Review, Vol. 70, No. 1, pp. 11-16, January, 1981 (Box 980, Folder 3)
    - "Energy Issues," American Oil and Gas Reporter, pp. 87-89, January, 1981 (Box 980, Folder 4)
    - "...But States Have Entered a New Era, Offer 'A Better Way,'" Governors Bulletin, May 8, 1981 (Box 980, Folder 5)
    - "Managing the New Federalism in Pennsylvania," Ripon Forum, Vol. 18, No. 1, pp. 6-10, January, 1982 (Box 980, Folder 6)
    - "Thornburgh Legally Speaking," Pennsylvania Lawyer, Vol. 4, No. 4, June 15, 1982 (Box 980, Folder 7)
    - "Message to Members of PA Pharmaceutical Association," Pennsylvania Pharmacist, Vol. 63, No. 10, pp. 246 and 264, October, 1982 (Box 980, Folder 8)
    - "Governor Dick Thornburgh Analyzes PA's Economy," PMA Outlook, Vol. 2, No. 1, pp. 5-19, Fall, 1982 (Box 980, Folder 9)
    - "Renewing Our Commitment," Holocaust Education, by Marcia Sachs Littell, Symposium Series, Vol. 13, pp. 1-5, October 24-26, 1982 (Box 980, Folder 10)
    - "Fast, Painless, Cures for Flaws in Shaping Federal Budgets," Business Week, p. 23, April 30, 1984 (Box 980, Folder 11)
    - "State Strategies and Incentives for Economic Development," Journal of Law and Commerce, Vol. 4, No. 1, 1984 (Box 980, Folder 12)
    - "Crisis Management: Ten Key Lessons From Three Mile Island Experience," Public Affairs Review, pp. 24-28, 1985 (Box 980, Folder 13)
    - "Innovation Through Application," Price Waterhouse Report regarding Conference on Innovation for Economic Growth, July 30, 1985 (Box 980, Folder 14)
    - "Congress, President Need Change to Constitution on Balancing the Budget," Governors Weekly Bulletin, NGA, 1986 (Box 980, Folder 15)
    - "Ten Lessons in Emergency Management," Capital Ideas, Governors Center at Duke University, November 1, 1986 (Box 980, Folder 16)
    - "The Case for Constitutionally Mandated Balanced Budget," Detroit College of Law Review, Vol. 1986, No. 4, Winter, 1986 (Box 980, Folder 17)
    - "TMI: Le Temoignage de Dick Thornburgh, Gouverneur de Pennsylvannie," (To be published as chapter in France), 1987 (Box 980, Folder 18)
    - "How Pennsylvania regained control of welfare," City & State, July, 1987 (Box 980, Folder 19)
    - Subject: The politics of deficit reduction: Ties that Bind: Debts, Deficits, Demographics, p. 80, Americans for Generational Equity Conference Proceedings, September 10-11, 1987 (Box 980, Folder 20)
    - "From the Star Car to the Governor's Office," Bulletin of the John F. Kennedy School of Government, Fall/Winter, 1987 (Box 980, Folder 21)
    - "Thoughts on the 1988 Campaign," Harvard Political Review, Vol. 15, No. 1, November, 1987 (Box 980, Folder 22)
    - Published remarks from Eagleton Institute of Politics, The Governor and the Legislature: "Office of Governor: Problems and Possibilities," Eagleton's 1987 Symposium on State of the States, 1988 (Box 980, Folder 23)
    - "The Pennsylvania Experience: The State's Role in an Era of Economic Transition," Economic Development Commentary, Vol. 12, No. 1, Spring, 1988 (Box 980, Folder 24)
    - "Thornburgh Looks Back and Ahead," PMA Quarterly, Vol. 1, No.1, April, 1988 (Box 980, Folder 25)
    - "Good Ethics is Good Government," Josephson Institute, Ethics, Spring/Summer, 1988 (Box 980, Folder 26)
    - "Gramm-Rudman-Hollings and the Balanced Budget Amendment," Harvard Journal on Legislation, Vol. 25, No. 2, Summer, 1988 (Box 981, Folder 1)
    - "Providing the Services our Citizens Want," County News, pp. 8a and 11a, August 1, 1988 (Box 981, Folder 2)
    - "The State's Role in an Era of Economic Transition: The Pennsylvania Experience, Economic Quarterly, Vol. 2, No. 3, August, 1988 (Box 981, Folder 3)
    - Thornburgh comments on "Hopes, Fears, and Federalism," by John E. Chubb, Nelson A. Rockefeller Center for the Social Sciences Occasional Papers Series, August 25, 1988 (Box 981, Folder 4)
    - "A Revitalized Concept of Public Service," Flintlock and Powderhorn, Vol. 6, No. 2, September, 1988 (Box 981, Folder 5)
    - "Challenges Facing State and Local Government," Forum, Vol. 3, No. 3, Fall, 1988 (Box 981, Folder 6)
    - "Reinvigorating Government," JFK School of Government, Bulletin, Fall/Winter, 1988 (Box 981, Folder 7)
    - "Richard Thornburgh Sets His Agenda," Legal Times, October 17, 1988 (Box 981, Folder 8)
    - "The FBI National Academy-A Symbol of Excellence," The Police Chief, November, 1988 (Box 981, Folder 9)
    - "Message from Attorney General Dick Thornburgh," Commissioner's Communique (INS), Vol. 2, No. 6, November/December, 1988 (Box 981, Folder 10)
    - "Thornburgh Seeks to Improve Coordination Between Law Enforcement Agencies," Subject to Debate, November/December, 1988 (Box 981, Folder 11)
    - "The Beat Officer-Preserving the Quality of Life," The Police Chief, Vol. 15, No. 12, December, 1988 (Box 981, Folder 12)
    - "Anti-Drug Abuse Act an Opportunity for Law Enforcement," The Police Chief, Vol. LVI, No. 1, January, 1989 (Box 981, Folder 13)
    - "For Police, Citizens Are Friends, As Well As Customers," Subject to Debate, Vol. 3, No. 1 (published by police executive research forum), January/February, 1989 (Box 981, Folder 14)
    - "Terrorism and the Inherent Conflict of Values," The Police Chief, March, 1989 (Box 981, Folder 15)
    - "The Growing International Role of the Justice Department," World Affairs Journal, Vol. 1, No. 1, April 24, 1989 (Box 981, Folder 16)
    - "Fighting 'Crime in the Suites,'" The Police Chief, April, 1989 (Box 981, Folder 17)
    - "A View from the Commission," Intergovernmental Perspective, Vol. 15, No. 3, Summer, 1989 (Box 981, Folder 18)
    - "A Great Success Story," The Pentacle, Vol. 9, No. 1, Summer/June, 1989 (Box 981, Folder 19)
    - "Proper Training of our Law Enforcement Personnel," The Field Training Quarterly, October, 1989 (Box 981, Folder 20)
    - "A Tale of Two Nations," ADL Bulletin (Anti-Defamation League), Vo. 46, No. 10, December, 1989 (Box 981, Folder 21)
    - Opening statement by AG, ADL of B'nai B'rith, 1988 ADL Audit of Anti-Semitic Incidents, 1989 (Box 981, Folder 22)
    - "A Focus on the Diverse Functions of DOJ: The War on Drugs," Federal Bar News & Journal, Vol. 37, No. 1, January, 1990 (Box 981, Folder 23)
    - "Uncle Sam Wants You-to Pay What You Owe the Government," USA Today, Vol. 118, No. 2536, January, 1990 (Box 981, Folder 24)
    - "A Message from the Attorney General," National Institute of Justice Bulletin, March, 1990 (Box 981, Folder 25)
    - "White Collar Crime: The Federal Response," The Commonwealth, Vol. 84, No. 15, April 9, 1990 (Box 981, Folder 26)
    - "The Soviet Union and the Rule of Law," Foreign Affairs, Vol. 69, No. 2, Spring, 1990 (Box 981, Folder 27)
    - "Boundless Energy," Tennessee Law Review, Vol. 57, No. 3, Spring, 1990 (Box 981, Folder 28)
    - "The Rule of Law in the Soviet Union: A Necessary Framework for Democratic Reform," The Heritage Lectures, July 10, 1990 (Box 981, Folder 29)
    - "The Rule of Law in the Soviet Union," Vital Speeches of the Day, Vol. LVI, No. 21, August 15, 1990 (Box 981, Folder 30)
    - "Firmly Committed to Enforce ADA," Worklife, Vol. 3, No. 3, Fall, 1990 (Box 981, Folder 31)
    - "Thornburgh Defends Muzzle on Prosecutors," Legal Times, November 12, 1990 (Box 981, Folder 32)
    - "Founding Values," New Dimensions: The Psychology Behind the News, November, 1990 (Box 981, Folder 33)
    - "The Americans with Disabilities Act," LABOR Law Journal, Vol. 41, No. 12, December, 1990 (Box 981, Folder 34)
    - "The Separation of Powers: An Exemplar of the Rule of Law," Washington University Law Quarterly, Vol. 68, No. 3, 1990 (Box 981, Folder 35)
    - Comments by Dick Thornburgh, The Lure of the Law, Richard W. Moll, pp.185-189, 1990 (Box 981, Folder 36)
    - "Law and Values in a Changing World," Vital Speeches of the Day, Vol. LVII, No. 7, January 15, 1991 (Box 981, Folder 37)
    - Published letter from AG Thornburgh regarding "What Happens to the Drugs After a Bust?" Ann Landers column, January 21, 1991 (Box 981, Folder 38)
    - "The Americans with Disabilities Act and the Future for Children," Exceptional Parent Magazine, Vol. 21, No. 2, March, 1991 (Box 981, Folder 39)
    - "White-Collar Crime: The Federal Response," The Commonwealth, March 23, 1991 (Box 981, Folder 40)
    - "Criminal Enforcement of Environmental Laws -A National Priority," The George Washington Law Review, Vol. 59, No. 4, April, 1991 (Box 981, Folder 41)
    - "Ethics and the Attorney General: The Attorney General Responds," Judicature, Vol. 74, No. 6, April-May, 1991 (Box 981, Folder 42)
    - "Prosecutors and the press in the search for the truth," Judicature, Vol. 75, No. 1, June-July, 1991 (Box 981, Folder 43)
    - "The Rule of Law in Eastern Europe," Cumberland Law Review, Vol. 21, p. 439, Summer, 1991 (Box 981, Folder 44)
    - "The Americans with Disabilities Act: Overcoming Barriers to Independence," Program Digest (National Easter Seal Society), Winter, 1991 (Box 981, Folder 45)
    - "Old United Nations: Putting UN in a Fitness Course," Foreign Service Journal, Vol. 70, No. 5, pp. 31-33, May, 1993 (Box 982, Folder 1)
    - "Today's United Nations in a Changing World," The American University Journal of International Law and Policy, Vol. 9, No. 1, pp. 215-223, Fall, 1993 (Box 982, Folder 2)
    - "Reform and Restructuring at the United Nations: A Progress Report," Nelson A. Rockefeller Center for Social Sciences, Dartmouth College Occasional Papers Series, 1993 (Box 982, Folder 3)
    - "Time for a Balanced-Budget Amendment," Congressional Record-Senate, S1997, February 28, 1994 (Box 982, Folder 4)
    - "The Saga of Cooper Companies: How NOT to Avoid Indictment," by Thornburgh and R. Adelman, K&L Securities Enforcement and Litigation Update, pp. 1-4, Spring, 1994 (Box 982, Folder 5)
    - "Election Observation Mission to Russia," International Republican Institute (IRI), Spring, 1994 (Box 982, Folder 6)
    - "The Saga of Cooper Companies: How NOT to Avoid Indictment," by Thornburgh and R. Adelman, Insights, Vol. 8, No. 9, September, 1994 (Box 982, Folder 7)
    - "The Internationalization of Business Crime," Transnational Organized Crime, Vol. 1, pp. 23-32, Spring, 1995 (Box 982, Folder 8)
    - "Doing What's Necessary to Fight Crime," Pennsylvania Lawyer, Vol. 17, No. 2, pp. 12-14, March-April, 1995 (Box 982, Folder 9)
    - "Incompetent Counsel in Capital Cases: A Root Cause of Delay in Habeas Corpus Proceedings," The Advocate, Vol. 17, No. 3, pp. 3-5, June, 1995 (Box 982, Folder 10)
    - "Selling Out Hong Kong Democracy," Legal Times, July 17, 1995 (Box 982, Folder 11)
    - "The Internationalization of Business Crime," White Collar Crime Reporter, Andrews Publications, Vol.9, No. 8, September, 1995 (Box 982, Folder 12)
    - Divided It Stands: Can the UN Really Work? by James Holtje, forward by Dick Thornburgh, Turner Publishing, Inc., 1995 (Box 982, Folder 13)
    - Forward by Governor Dick Thornburgh and Governor Dick Celests, co-chairs of State-Federal Technology Partnership; Partnerships: A Compendium of State and Federal Cooperative Technology Programs, Christopher Coburn, Editor, 1995 (Box 982, Folder 14)
    - "The Federal Role in Economic Development: Definitions, Issues, and Options," National Academy of Public Administration (NAPA) Panel (paper submitted), January 26, 1996 (Box 982, Folder 15)
    - "High Noon for Civil Justice Reform," The Metropolitan Corporate Counsel, Vol. 4, No. 2, February, 1996 (Box 982, Folder 16)
    - "Punitive Damage Awards After BMW v. Gore," Legal Backgrounder, Vol. 11, No. 27, July 26, 1996 (Box 982, Folder 17)
    - Introduction, p. v, " Civil Justice Reform: What Now?," Briefly...Perspectives on Legislation, Regulation, and Litigation, No. 3, November, 1996 (Box 982, Folder 18)
    - "Business Crime Goes International," Common Sense, Republican Journal of Fact and Opinion, No. 9, pp. 75-85, Winter, 1996 (Box 982, Folder 19)
    - "Toward an Effective and Efficient United Nations," American Leadership Conference, Washington Times Foundation, 1996 (Box 982, Folder 20)
    - "America's Civil Justice Dilemma: The Prospects for Reform," Maryland Law Review, Vol. 5, No.4, 1996 (Box 982, Folder 21)
    - Introduction by Dick Thornburgh, Citizen Suite and Qui Tam Actions: Private Enforcement of Public Policy by Blanch, Cohen Gerson, Slavitt. Published by National Legal Center for the Public Interest, 1996 (Box 982, Folder 22)
    - "Tort Reform and the 1996 Election" by Dick Thornburgh and Genevieve Matthews, The Alert, Newsletter of Federal Bar Association's Corporate & Association Counsel's Division, Vol. 5, No.5, January, 1997 (Box 982, Folder 23)
    - "Junk Science Makes Junk Law," National Review, Vol. XLIX, No. 5, March 24, 1997 (Box 982, Folder 24)
    - "The Rule of Law in Hong Kong: Some Implications for U.S. Policy," Journal of International Economic Law, University of Pittsburgh, Vol. 18, No. 1, Spring, 1997 (Box 982, Folder 25)
    - "The Search for 'The Truth, The Whole Truth and Nothing but the Truth' in the Criminal Justice System," Iowa Advocate, pp. 8-9, (Excerpted from speech to University of Iowa School of Law, Spring/Summer, 1997 (Box 982, Folder 26)
    - "Supreme Court Should Confirm Trial Judges' Authority to Review Scientific Evidence," Legal Opinion Letter of the Washington Legal Foundation, September 26, 1997 (Box 982, Folder 27)